Vanja Tarasov

Khabarovsk, Khabarovsk, Russia



albertalexeyev523@hotmail.com



linkedin.com/in/albert-alexeyev-535164220

Summary

I started my career as a front-end developer but I love logical thinking and I always look for the hardest problems to solve.

So these days I prefer working as a back-end engineer.

Furthermore information has been vital for a business all the time so I love working in companies which are developing data driven products.

Experience



Full Stack Engineer

Self-employed

Aug 2021 - Present (2 months +)

Full Stack Engineer

PicnicHealth

Dec 2020 - Jul 2021 (8 months)

- Worked on React/Node/Express-based application, validating query string with regex.
- Communicated with clients and presented any changes I made.
- Refactored large methods of multiple reusable and maintainable methods.
- Wrote unit tests with Jest and Enzyme, documented every change made to the code base.

Full Stack Engineer

LiveGlam

Sep 2019 - Nov 2020 (1 year 3 months)

- Created inventory management system in React from scratch
- Created mobile app with Java for Android
- Developed inventory management system back-end using Python Django
- Added elastic search to the production site

bite Full Stack Engineer

Bite

Feb 2018 - Jun 2019 (1 year 5 months)

- Built reusable components to enhance the development process and use Typescript for strict typechecking.
- Developed a robust ordering platform with React and Vue is and solved fault-tolerant and architectural problems in AWS.
- Contributed to an auto-scaling system using AWS auto-scaling and AWS SQS to handle multiple requests in one AWS EC2 instance.
- Built the Docker environment which contained several microservices in one script.

- Contributed backend development with Ruby on Rails.

React Native Developer

SHORTLINK

Apr 2016 - Nov 2017 (1 year 8 months)

- Built internal city management mobile app in React Native
- Added arcgis custom map feature
- Used redux-saga as state management
- Developed rest apis in Java Spring framework

Frontend Developer

Ellipsis Health

Apr 2014 - 2016 (2 years 9 months)

- Primarily tasked with the creation of a serving application built using Angular and Material-UI.
- Provided ongoing bug fixes and enhancements to our existing internal applications.
- Utilized Jest and Enzyme for front-end unit testing.
- Contributed backend development with Laravel.

Frontend Developer

CloudScale Corporation

Nov 2011 - Feb 2014 (2 years 4 months)

- Converted web app was written by Ember.js to Next.js with Typescript.
- Focused on mobile-first development and used CSS-in-JS library, emotion, with Next.js.
- Contributed backend development with Java Spring Boot.
- Collaborated with the back-end team using swagger UI to get API definitions.
- Wrote unit tests and integration tests with react-testing-library.

Education



Georgia State University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science Sep 2007 - Aug 2011

Skills

Node.js • React.js • Django • Data Analysis • Laravel • React Native • Ruby on Rails • Vue.js • Java • AngularJS